Guide to the Glenway Wescott Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Oversize, 17.66; (13 boxes)
  Series II, III, IV, VII, VII, and IX.
  - Continual Lessons, photographic negatives from publishers (in Series II), 1992 (Box 472, Folder 5278)
  - The Love of New York, printed version [as "I Love New York"], Harper's Bazaar (in Series III), 1943 Dec (Box 472, Folder 5279)
  - This Way Out [The Runaways], printed version, Collier's (in Series III), 1925 Jul 4 (Box 472, Folder 5280)
  - "A Surpassing Sequel", review of The Wapshot Scandal, printed version, Book Week (in Series III), 1964 Jan 5 (Box 472, Folder 5281)
  - "All of us on the half-shell", review of The Oysters of Locmariaquer, printed version, Book Week (in Series III), 1964 Jul 12 (Box 472, Folder 5282)
  - Printed version, [as "Subjects before he predicates"], Book Week (in Series III), 1964 Oct 4 (Box 472, Folder 5283)
  - Printed version, [as "She knew what it was all about"], Book Week (in Series III), 1964 Jun 21 (Box 472, Folder 5284)
  - Printed version, as "Not a Proper Englishman", Book Week, 1963 Oct 27 (Box 472, Folder 5285)
  - Printed version [as "A Dinner, A Talk, A Walk with Forster"], New York Times Book Review (in Series III), 1971 Oct 10 (Box 472, Folder 5286)
  - "Illustrations of Mythology", printed version, US Camera (in Series III), 1939 (Box 472, Folder 5287)
  - "The Passing of the Old Party", printed version [long and short], Life (in Series III), 1966 Jan 14 (Box 473, Folder 5288)
  - "A Record of Friendship", Kanin's Remembering Mr. Maugham ", printed version, New York Times Book Review (in Series III), 1966 Oct 9 (Box 473, Folder 5289)
  - Printed version [as "A face to laugh, A face to cry"], Book Week (in Series III), 1965 May 2 (Box 473, Folder 5290)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, "The Last of the Lost Generation", printed version, Esquire (in Series III), 1963 Jul (Box 473, Folder 5291)
  - Photographs: GW by Abbé, James, Sr. (in Series VII), ca. 1927 (Box 474, Folder 5292)
  - Photographs: GW by Adams, Ansel (in Series VII), ca. 1940s-50s (Box 474, Folder 5293)
  - Photographs: GW by Ciavolino, M. (in Series VII), 1958 (Box 474, Folder 5294)
  - Photographs GW by Francos, J. B. (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 474, Folder 5295)
  - Photographs: GW by Lynes, George Platt (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 474, Folder 5296-5297)
  - Photographs: GW by Stevenson, John (in Series VII), 1983 (Box 474, Folder 5298)
  - Photographs: GW by Ulmann, Doris (in Series VII), ca. 1929 (Box 474, Folder 5299-5300)
  - Photographs: GW by Unidentified (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 474, Folder 5301)
  - Photographs: GW with Moore, Marianne, at MacDowell Colony (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 474, Folder 5302)
  - Photographs: GW with Porter, Katherine Anne, at publisher's party for Ship of Fools (in Series VII), 1962 Apr 2 (Box 474, Folder 5303)
  - Photographs: GW with Wescott, Josephine (in Series VII), 1958 (Box 474, Folder 5304)
  - Photographs: MW by Abbé, James, Sr. (in Series VII), ca. 1926 (Box 474, Folder 5305)
  - Photographs: MW by Adams, Ansel (in Series VII), ca. 1940s-50s (Box 474, Folder 5306)
  - Photographs: MW by Adams, Ansel (in Series VII), ca. 1940s-50s (Box art, Folder 5306a)
  - Photographs: MW by Lynes, George Platt (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 474, Folder 5307-5310)
  - Photographs: MW by Roehle, E. (in Series VII), 1917 (Box 474, Folder 5311)
  - Photographs: MW by Lynes, George Platt (in Series VII), ca. 1938 (Box 475, Folder 5312)
  - Photographs: MW with Rodgers, Richard, Mrs. (in Series VII), 1948 (Box 475, Folder 5313)
  - Citation: from Karen Horney Clinic thanking GW for role in 1960 Art Show (in Series IV), 1960 Jun 18 (Box 475, Folder 5314)
  - Degree: honorary doctor of letters, Rutgers University (in Series IV), 1963 Jun (Box 475, Folder 5315)
  - Photographs: MW Scrapbook (in Series VII), ca. 1900-45 (Box 476, Folder 5316)
  - Photographs by Stevenson, John (in Series VII), 1980 (Box 477, Folder 5317-5328)
  - Photographs: Baldwin, Billy (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 478, Folder 5329)
  - Photographs: Bull, Wesson (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 478, Folder 5330)
  - Photographs: Cobb, Eliza Bliss Parkinson (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 478, Folder 5331)
  - Photographs: Cromwell, Dick (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 478, Folder 5332)
  - Photographs: Daniels, Jimmy (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 478, Folder 5333)
  - Photographs: Ford, Ford Madox (in Series VII), 1932 (Box 478, Folder 5334)
  - Photographs: Levy, Joella [with Wesson Bull?] (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 478, Folder 5335)
  - Photographs: Maugham, W. Somerset (in Series VII), ca. 1940s-50s (Box 478, Folder 5336)
  - Photographs: Miller, William Christian (in Series VII), 1944 (Box 478, Folder 5337)
  - Photographs: Moore, Marianne, in Brooklyn antique shop (in Series VII), ca. 1963 (Box 478, Folder 5338)
  - Photographs: Moore, Marianne, with her bust by Gaston Lachaise (in Series VII), 1963 (Box 478, Folder 5339)
  - Photographs: Moore, Marianne, with her mother at 260 Cumberland Street, Brooklyn (in Series VII) (Box 478, Folder 5340)
  - Photographs: Ney, Elly (in Series VII), 1916-22, n.d. (Box 478, Folder 5341)
  - Photographs: Porter, Katherine Anne (in Series VII), ca. 1950s (Box 479, Folder 5342)
  - Photographs: Porter, Katherine Anne posed at typewriter (in Series VII), 1950 or 1958 (Box 479, Folder 5343)
  - Photographs: Saportas, Marion Tiffany (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 479, Folder 5344)
  - Photographs: Sitwell, Edith (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 479, Folder 5345)
  - Photographs: [Taulberg, W.?] (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 479, Folder 5346)
  - Photographs: Wescott Family: Wescott, Barbara, and Lloyd Wescott (in Series VII), 1958 (Box 479, Folder 5347)
  - Photographs: Unidentified (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 479, Folder 5348)
  - Photographs: Street scene with children (in Series VII), n.d. (Box 479, Folder 5349)
  - Photographs: Wheeler, Fred Monroe (in Series VII), ca. 1935-40 (Box 479, Folder 5350)
  - Photographs: Group of men at Stage Door Canteen (in Series VII), 1943 Feb 17 (Box 479, Folder 5351)
  - Photographs: "Conversation Piece" scrapbook, ca. 1939-40 (Box 480, Folder 5352)
  - Artwork originals: [Dufy, Raoul?], etching "Chapitre VII, Garcon" (in Series VIII), n.d. (Box 481, Folder 5353)
  - Artwork orginals: Forbes, Donald, portrait of MW, oil on canvas (in Series VIII), ca. 1937 (Box art, Folder 5353a)
  - Artwork originals: Harris, William, portrait of MW, silverpoint (in Series VIII), 1952 (Box art, Folder 5353b)
  - Artwork orginals: Littlefield, William H., portrait of MW, charcoal and pencil (in Series VIII), 1936 Oct 16 (Box art, Folder 5353c)
  - Artwork orginals: Littlefield, William H., portrait of MW, oil on canvas, 1936 Oct 16 (Box art, Folder 5353)
  - Artwork orginals: Frasconi, [Antonio], "The Cat Reformed by Matrimony," ink and wash (in Series VIII) (Box bsd, folder 5353e)
  - Artwork originals: Perlin, Bernard, portraits of GW and MW, silverpoint (in Series VIII), 1945-48 (Box art, 5353f–art, 5353j)
  - Artwork originals: Perlin, Bernard portrait of MW, wax pencil (in Series VIII), 1965 (Box art, Folder 5353k)
  - Artwork originals: Tchelitchew, Pavel, portrait of MW, ink and wash, 1935 (Box art, Folder 5353l)
  - Images of People (in Series VIII), n.d. (Box 481, Folder 5354)
  - Reproductions of Artwork: General (in Series VIII), 1950s-80s (Box 481, Folder 5355)
  - Reproductions of Artwork: Picasso, Pablo (in Series VIII), ca. 1950s (Box 481, Folder 5356)
  - Reproductions of Artwork: Tchelitchew, Pavel (in Series VIII), 1942, 1951 (Box 481, Folder 5357)
  - Clippings: Animals and Nature (in Series IX) (Box 482, Folder 5358)
  - Clippings: Architecture and Design (in Series IX), ca. 1946-87 (Box 482, Folder 5359)
  - Clippings: Art, general (in Series IX), ca. 1936-90 (Box 482, Folder 5360-5364)
  - Clippings: Art, images (in Series IX), ca. 1931-82 (Box 483, Folder 5365)
  - Clippings: Book reviews (in Series IX), ca. 1938-87 (Box 483, Folder 5366-5367)
  - Clippings: Current events (in Series IX), ca. 1934-90 (Box 483, Folder 5368)
  - Clippings: Dance (in Series IX), ca. 1952-87 (Box 483, Folder 5369)
  - Clippings: Fashion (in Series IX), ca. 1933-70 (Box 483, Folder 5370)
  - Clippings: Essays and articles (in Series IX), ca. 1953-86 (Box 483, Folder 5371-5373)
  - Clippings: Food and recipes (in Series IX), ca. 1969-84 (Box 484, Folder 5374)
  - Clippings: People, "A"-"L" (in Series IX), ca. 1933-86 (Box 484, Folder 5375)
  - Clippings: Moore, Marianne (in Series IX), ca. 1957-86 (Box 484, Folder 5376)
  - Clippings: People, "M"-"O" (in Series IX), ca. 1922-84 (Box 484, Folder 5377)
  - Clippings: Porter, Katherine Anne (in Series IX), ca. 1951-80 (Box 484, Folder 5378)
  - Clippings: People, "R" (in Series IX), ca. 1951-79 (Box 484, Folder 5379)
  - Clippings: Rothschild, Philippe and Pauline (in Series IX), ca. 1962-75 (Box 484, Folder 5380)
  - Clippings: People, "S"-"Y" (in Series IX), ca. 1948-84 (Box 484, Folder 5381)
  - Clippings: People, Groups (in Series IX), ca. 1950-73 (Box 484, Folder 5382)
  - Clippings: Theater (in Series IX), ca. 1962-84 (Box 484, Folder 5383)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.42; (1 box)
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 11 (Box 485, Folder 5384)
  - Box 1, folder 16 (Box 485, Folder 5385)
  - Box 1, folder 17 (Box 485, Folder 5386)
  - Box 2, folder 19 (Box 485, Folder 5387)
  - Box 466, folder 5188a (Box 485, Folder 5388)
  - Box 466, folder 5210a (Box 485, Folder 5389)